Contact

melayda@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/melayda (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Hospitals

Emergency Room

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

TNCC, ENPC

Honors-Awards

10 Year Service Award

Mindy Elayda MPA, BSN, RN

Staff Nurse III at Kaiser Permanente

Roseville. California

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with over 22 years of acute care experience in Level I, Level II trauma centers and pediatric emergency departments. I am open to consulting and injury prevention/community outreach opportunities to enhance my career. I graduated in December 2015 from Grand Canyon University for Master's Degree in Public Administration with an emphasis in Health Management.

Specialties:

Charge Nurse experience in various ER settings.

Pediatric ER and Trauma Experience in Level I and Level II Trauma Centers.

Computer Documentation programs; EPIC, CERNA, Allscripts
Proficient in managing and prioritizing deadlines
Strong clinical judgement

Certifications: ACLS, PALS, BLS, TNCC, ENPC,

Experience

Kaiser Permanente

11 years 5 months

Staff Nurse III

May 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Roseville

32 hour days-shift in Level II large 70+bed suburban ER in Placer County. I am currently a member of Pediatric ER Committee and Sepsis Committee that are geared to improving the quality of care at Kaiser Roseville ER. A resource to travel nurses, new staff and student nurses. . Kaiser Roseville is a specialized hospital with Womens' & Children's Hospital.

Staff Nurse II
June 2016 - May 2018 (2 years)
South Sacramento, CA

Level II Trauma Center in South Sacramento. 41 bed ER with 6 ER bed Observation Unit. High volume ER seeing 200-400 patients daily. Fast patient turnaround due to Rapid Care-(1 hour turnaround time) and Frontline zones -(ambulatory zone with acuity level 3 that require only 2-3 hour patient care) which help expediate ER throughput along with the utilization of the TAS patient assignment system. Kaiser South Sacramento is Kaiser Permanente's 1st trauma center with a helipad and teaching hospital for UC Davis Medical School Residents. I am currently working 8 hour dayshifts.

Charge Nurse

February 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 5 months)

San Rafael, CA

Evening shift Charge Nurse in Level III Trauma Center in suburban Marin County. As leader of the health care team, collaborates with: ER MDs, RNs, ER Techs, ancillary staff. Directs shift-to-shift departmental operations, providing high quality patient care and utilizing the nursing process in accordance with the current standards of care, policies and procedures. Expert resource and leader in the emergency department to be effective in resource allocation by ensuring appropriate patient care assignments, staffing and scheduling. Adaptable to ongoing changing dynamics of the emergency department and to be effective in emergency department throughput.

Staff Nurse II

March 2009 - February 2015 (6 years)

San Francisco

Staff Nurse II

Kaiser Permanente Medical Center-San Francisco

Level II ER. Chest Pain Center and Stroke Certified ER in an urban setting.

Teaching Hospital for UCSF residents

Member of ER workplace/safety committe

John Muir Health

RN III

April 2011 - April 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Concord, CA

12 hour per diem day/evening shift in the Emergency Department at John Muir Medical Center. 44 bed ER Magnet Hospital and Certified Stroke/Chest Pain Center.

.

Sutter Solano Medial Center

Staff Nurse II March 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 6 months) Vallejo

Per Diem 12 hour day and night shifts.36-40 hours per week. Relief Day Shift Charge Nurse. SuperUser for I-Stat Point of Care for the Emergency Department. Orient new staff and student nurses. Attended monthly ER collaboration meetings. Primary pediatric nurse for Asthma Study with Dr Ron Dieckman to improve quality of care for children with asthma ages 0-16.

Medical Staffing Network RN

June 2007 - September 2009 (2 years 4 months)

Calfornia and Arizona

Temporary per diem nursing agency for various ERs in Northern California and Tucson, AZ.

St. Mary's Medical Center ER; San Francisco, CA

Alta Bates/Summit Medical Center ER Oakland, CA

Doctor's Hospital ER San Pablo, CA

Sutter Solano Medical Center ER Vallejo, CA

Northwestern Hospital ER Tucson, AZ

Tucson Heart Hospital ER: Tucson, AZ (Carondelet Heart and Vascular Institute)

University of Arizona Medical Center-Main Campus ER: Tucson, AZ

AMN Healthcare RN-Traveler January 2000 - March 2008 (8 years 3 months) Various Locations

Travel Nurse 13 week contracts in ER.

UCSF Medical Center, Jan 2000 to April 2000 and Feb 2004- May 2004

John Muir Medical Center, Walnut Creek- Aug 2002 to Dec 2002

St Luke's Hospital, San Francisco, CA May 2004-July 2004

Sharp Grossmont Medical Center: La Mesa, CA July 2004-Oct 2004

St.Mary's Medical Center: Tucson, AZ: Aug 2005-June 2006

UMC-Kino Campus: Tucson, AZ: June 2006-Sept 2006

Stanford University Hospital Medical Center: Sept 2006-Dec 2006 and Nov

2007-June 2008

HRN Services RN-Traveler July 2007 - September 2007 (3 months) San Francsico, CA

13 week travel assignment at St Francis Memorial Hospital, San Francisco, CA 12 hour days shifts/full time in the ER,

Stanford University Medical Center RN-traveler September 2006 - December 2006 (4 months) Stanford, CA

Traveler RN and was hired for 2 travel assignments in September 2006 and November 2007- June 2008. 12 hour day shifts, full time 36 hours/week. Busy Level I teaching hospital/trauma center with 8 bed Pediatric ER. Adult and Pediatric Trauma experience. High acuity Level 1 ER. Resource for new travelers in 2006 and rehired as a traveler in 2006 for transition from paper charting to EPIC.

RN-Traveler
August 2005 - June 2006 (11 months)
RN traveler at St Mary Hospital in Tucson, AZ.

Large 55 bed ER. Level II ER. Extended travel assignment 5 times.

Kaiser Permanente Regional Medical Equipment Consultant November 2004 - August 2005 (10 months)

Carondelet Health Network

Oakland, CA

Transferred into postion from being a Staff Nurse II at Kaiser Walnut Creek ER.

Evalutes, locates and recommends euqipment to be purchased for new facilities, major renovations and expansions of exisiting medical facilities. Identifies equipment and design conflicts during the design process to aovid costly construction delays. Primary Medical Equipment Consultant (MEC) at Kaiser Regional. Ensures conpliance with JCAHO and other regulatory standards for equipment installation and use. Works with outside architectural consultants and contractors to review drawings, work to reconcile drawings functionality, and note design/equipment conflicts. Repsonsible for for providing equipment lists within established Kaiser Permanente National Standards and budget.

Kaiser Permanente Walnut Creek Medical Center Staff Nurse II August 1998 - July 2005 (7 years)

Part time employment on evenings/days 32 hours week
Large 45 bed ER. Team Leader (Charge Nurse), resource for new grads and
new employees, MSE/triage.

UCSF Medical Center RN-Traveler February 2004 - April 2004 (3 months) San Francisco. CA

2nd travel assignment at UCSF Medical Center in the ER.
Busy, urban Level II teaching hospital.
13 week contract. 12 hour rotating days/night shifts.
1st travel contract with UCSF 4/2001-7-2001

John Muir Health RN-Traveler August 2002 - December 2002 (5 months)

13 week Travel Assignement via Cross Country Travel Company12 hours evening shift 11-11p and working in Level II Trauma Center,Intial travel contract at John Muir Medical Center 10/2001-4/2002

UC Davis Medical Center Clinical Nurse II November 1997 - July 1998 (9 months) Sacramento, CA Full-time 12 hour day shift at E-3. Adult med-surg overflow and peds/adolescent unit.

Education

Grand Canyon University

Master's degree, Public Administration with an emphasis in Health Care Management \cdot (2014 - 2015)

California State University-Sacramento BSN, Nursing · (1995 - 1997)